Guide to the Sullivan-Stewart Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Sullivan-Stewart papers
1828-1857
MS 1186
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
Chiefly letters written to William Stewart, lawyer and politician, who was a member of the Pennsylvania House of Representatives, and subsequently a Republican member of Congress from Pennsylvania (1857-1861). The letters, which antedate his service in Congress, are largely from his in-laws, Charles and Moses Sullivan, who were themselves State Senators in Pennsylvania. They discuss Pennsylvania politics and local economic conditions.
Sullivan family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Arthur M. Brown, 1939.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of letters (1828-1857) to William Stewart, politician of Butler, Pennsylvania, one letter to his wife, Margaret Sullivan, and a few to his daughter Amanda (1841, 1861). The principal writers are Moses and Charles C. Sullivan, also politicians of Butler. Charles was Margaret Stewart's brother, and Moses was also related to her. Their letters are, however, more political than personal. The other correspondents are all Pennsylvanian politicians.
The main segments of the correspondence are:
1829-1838: Moses Sullivan, then State Senator in Harrisburg, to Stewart in Butler
1841: various Pennsylvanian politicians to Stewart, then chief clerk of the Treasury in Harrisburg
1842-1844: Charles Sullivan, then State Senator in Harrisburg, to Stewart in Butler
1854-1855: various Pennsylvanian politicians to Stewart, then State Representative in Harrisburg
Biographical / Historical
William Stewart was born in Mercer, Pennsylvania, on September 10, 1810. He attended public schools and then graduated from Jefferson College in Canonsburg, Pennsylvania. He studied law and was admitted to the bar in Pennsylvania, where he began a practice in his hometown of Mercer. Stewart was first a member of the Pennsylvania state congress and was then elected to the United States Congress, where he served two terms (1857-1861). Following his years in congress, Stewart returned to the practice of law. He died in Mercer, on October 17, 1876.
Pennsylvania -- Economic conditions; Pennsylvania -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865; Middle Atlantic States; United States -- Politics and government; Lawyers; Legislators; Politicians; Stewart, William, 1810-1876; Sullivan, Charles C.; Sullivan, Moses, 1786-1839; Stuart family; Sullivan family; United States. Congress
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - 1828 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1829 Jan-Apr (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1829 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1830 Jan-Mar (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1830 Dec-1831 Mar (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1831 Dec-1832 Apr (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1833 Jan (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1836 Jan-Jul (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1837-1838 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1841 Feb-Jun (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1841 Jul-Dec (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1842 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1843-1844 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1854-1857 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1857, 1861, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)